The starting point of MyTwin was
MyTwin first, before MyTwinLab.
I'm going to explain to you
what MyTwin is, above all.
The starting point is
simple: I lost both my parents,
my mother to a medical error,
my father to a lack of
prevention, on his own part.
And when you're dealing with a medical
emergency, when you're supporting
your loved ones, or yourself,
with regard to your own
health, you're constantly
searching for solutions.
You're struggling.
And you ask yourself: What's
going on? I don't understand.
With doctors, you can feel that
they don't necessarily have the time
to answer us.
We don't get the right answers.
We sense that there may be
solutions that exist
somewhere, but we don't know where
they are, we don't know how
they work, they're
not... We saw that in a
hospital, but in the end, they're
no longer in place, it was
just an experiment.
So you end up asking yourself
a lot of questions and searching
for all this a bit desperately.
So that's how I
started telling myself: What are
the solutions? Where are
they? I'm going to find them, I'm
going to identify them, and once
and for all, I'm going to
unify them.
I'm going to bring them
all together in one place.
Because when you find a
solution for issues
related to diabetes, maybe
when you have diabetes, you
also have endometriosis.
Maybe you also have
another disease.
So actually, it makes no
sense to have a single solution
isolated in its own corner.
All the solutions,
the effective preventive ideas,
need to come together in one place,
interact with one
another and be able to talk to each other,
communicate for the well-being
of the patient.
So that's how
MyTwin got started.
And so, as you'll have understood,
MyTwin is a solution that
brings together within one
single app all the
solutions available on the
market, the most
advanced, the most reliable ones.
With the goal of making everyone...
of giving back to everyone
control and knowledge
of their health, of information.
In fact, there's a real desire
for patients to no longer be
in a kind of passivity
regarding their health.
That's what we call
4P medicine: preventive, predictive,
personalized and proactive.
We put back into the hands of the citizen,
the end user, the
patient, the right to information,
access to information, access
to care and the ability to
trigger services with
a single click.
And it's an app
you have in your pocket
on iOS or Android.
So it's very
easy to use.
So, a quick question,
because doctors
are very protective of their knowledge.
How do they react when
you offer this kind of
solution? Is the medical
profession skeptical? Or,
on the contrary, are there doctors
who understand that if the
patient is informed and also
in charge, once again
responsible for their
health, things go...
it's complicated, I mean, to create
a new solution like that
in a very old-fashioned environment
with codes of secrecy and
not sharing information. Yeah,
well, maybe I'm
lucky, maybe I'm telling
the right story.
For now, we haven't had
any particular problems, we've
had enthusiasm, rather.
We've even... In fact, the
common response I get every time from
doctors or from executives in
health institutions,
insurers or others, is: Finally.
Finally, a real opportunity.
Finally, we know it's
time to come together, to work
together, it no longer makes sense otherwise.
And above all, what makes
everyone want to come together is that
today, most health
companies fail.
80% of health companies in
AI are going to,
they're going to go under.
That's a reality.
So at some point,
you have to do
something, you have to react.
So there, they see an
opportunity and say: OK,
this app is going to bring us together.
And then, there may be
some resistant doctors, there
certainly are, but it doesn't matter.
For me, that's not my problem.
Yes, you take those who are
willing and who
understand your project.
So MyTwinLab is
another project.
I mean, it's MyTwin on a broader scale, with
other partners? Yes, so what
you need to understand about MyTwin,
first, is that, here, I've
explained it simply: it's
an app that
integrates lots of apps in one
place so that we have
complete access to all the health
solutions.
Which is already very, very good.
But beyond that,
the mission and vision we have
are bigger than all of us, because we
are creating what we
call a digital twin.
Now, you're in
tech, so
you know what that is.
Why? Because
quite simply, as soon as
your medical record is
connected to an LLM and, on top of
that, it's going to be connected to all
the health apps within
one single place, you
start to have quite a lot
of information about a person.
And eventually, it can start
to create, let's say,
the avatar, the digital twin
of that person.
And that's what we do.
We're creating the most advanced
digital twin of patient
health in the world.
Why? Because it's
thanks to a community.
And that may be the
difference with ChatGPT Health...
or Claude for Healthcare.
What we tell ourselves is, given
that I started from
my point of view as a citizen patient
who had, who has, well, who had
setbacks in healthcare with
my parents, the first
thing we tell ourselves is
ultimately, as
a user, as a
patient, when we use AI,
whatever it may be, or when
we use tools like
this one, why shouldn't I
also be involved in
building these tools? Knowing
how we're building ourselves.
What are our ideas for
tomorrow? What are the
next features
we're going to roll out? Do
you have
skills to help us
create these next
features? That's
MyTwinLab.
Being able to welcome into the
lab the average
person, who can quite
simply tell us their
health story, which is
already data that's very
valuable, because feedback,
stories,
anecdotes are what drive and
what trigger emotion
and collective movement.
First level of contribution,
very simple: share your
health story, we all have
one, we all have them.
Second level of contribution:
I'm a tech person, I'm a
doctor, I'm a researcher,
I'm a student, I'm
passionate about health,
I want to go further.
And then, we can actually
create the next features
together, AIs that
will be able
to read an X-ray better.
We're working on endometriosis
at the moment, on the brain,
other features that
matter to you in terms of
your values, in terms of your
issues, which are
your own, and in terms of your
sensitivities.
Tools should reflect who you are,
what you
are and what you
want to become. So we're all
about community, building
community and the contribution
of members.
So, we clearly understand the
difference compared to ChatGPT
Health, especially since
obviously, all the LLMs are
creating their own services.
It's no coincidence that they've
moved into this data and
into this form of support.
For you, when we talk about
ChatGPT Health, what
opportunity or danger do you see? Well,
when you heard that announcement,
how did you react? I mean, how did it
make you feel, as an entrepreneur,
but also as a citizen,
a patient, knowing where
your data is?
So, what was your reaction
to an announcement that was
pretty big three weeks ago,
I think? Yes, three
weeks ago, ChatGPT Health came out, and two
days later, Claude for Healthcare, and
I hope that in a while,
Mistral Health, that would be the
logical next step.
So, personally,
I had two reactions.
The first, very positive.
I'm convinced that the
world of tomorrow will be incredible.
I'm a very positive person by nature.
And I think that's
important in the story we
tell and in the choices we
make, in the media.
If we're positive,
we'll create positive things.
We'll think about it that way.
Anyway, first positive reaction:
first of all, for us,
it allowed us to position ourselves
and to say: That's it.
Some pretty big players
are getting into this. The evolution,
it was expected.
We knew it was going to happen.
We'd been doing it ourselves in our
own corner for over a year already.
So positive, because for us, as
a player, it gives us
something to aim for,
to position ourselves, to look at
what they're going to do.
And ultimately, for us, what
market share we're going to take.
We're a company,
we have to make money.
So how are we going to position ourselves?
What's our
storytelling going to be? What's our
message going to be? And, ultimately, what
market are we going to
conquer? And how are we going to
position ourselves with that? First
very positive thing for us.
Second positive thing too, because
it's a disruptive innovation
that moves all of healthcare forward,
which means that, behind it,
it inevitably makes us ask questions.
Here we are today,
doctors are starting to
talk about it, health
institutions are talking about it, they're
saying: Wait, we're out of
time, we need to act. That's
very positive.
The other side is: Ah, yet another
company, if I'm caricaturing,
that's going to dominate the world,
and this time, in the health sector.
What do we do? Well, we've
made the choice of saying that
our product, we're creating it with you
and we're creating it together.
And why not even,
at some point,
own it together.
We could very well share the
shares of our business
with the community of users.
For us, it's super important
to head in that direction, eventually.
So, I think that's the
danger point: telling
ourselves we're going to end up again
in 10 years with one, two,
three companies that are going to
dominate the market and that
will eventually be able to do whatever
they want.
But it's not just because
they're American.
And that's maybe a
slightly different point,
but we can have
European or French players.
Being French doesn't mean
you necessarily do the right
things in the long run.
All the health players that
are succeeding today
in AI for prediction and
prevention, their market
is 80% in the US or in Asia.
When they get bought out,
when the investment funds
exit, etc., what choices
will they make? We have no idea.
For us, the only safeguard
we've found is to say
from day one, we're
building with the users.
It's the users who
co-create the solutions and
who co-own the solutions.
So an entrepreneur's
responsibility with a vision of
the common good, of sharing from the
start, indeed, outside of a
purely capitalist logic, but
aware that there are indeed
monopolies that need to be
fought, that are
forming. After that, everyone is free
to choose the solution based
on their values or on where they're
willing to hand over their
personal data, their health data.
To wrap up, since you're
positive, you're optimistic, it's
rather nice to
hear, because I'm
kind of... I share your
feeling that negative self-fulfilling
prophecies, there are
a lot of them.
What's the future of healthcare? In
2050, what's your picture of
what healthcare will be like? I think that
within 10 years, Léa, 70% of the
world's population will have
their health digital twin
in their pocket.
In my opinion, it's a certainty.
There's already ChatGPT Health, so it's
a first, a first
building block, a first start.
A lot of people
use GPT, so
it's going to move very, very fast.
And you know, I was saying this a
year ago and at one point, people said:
You might be a little
optimistic. Now...
it's reality.
So, I think we'll all have
our digital twin, our
virtual representation
of our health and our
body in our pocket,
like the one we're creating.
And we'll be able to access
almost all possible health
services in terms
of prediction and prevention.
So, we'll be very proactive.
And at the same time, the LLM
will be there to guide us through
our care pathway in
a very personalized way.
For us, there will be as many MyTwin
apps as there are users.
If you're a woman and you have
endometriosis, you... Thank you
very much, Rubens, for these
positive words, which also feel good.
Do you have any
questions? We have time to
take one or two questions,
if health inspires you
or if you have any questions
about the work of
Rubens, of Ystart.
No? We've worn you out.
Well, thank you very much, Rubens.
I'm just going to... There was a
question? Sorry, I didn't see.
I'm not from the younger
generation, I'm from the older one.
Hello.
So I'm from the older
generation, and I have a bit of trouble
understanding how all this,
this dematerialized material,
can materialize.
In the example you're giving
about healthcare, I hear
that you're talking about a
digital twin, but on the
other hand, in France at least,
we don't have doctors, we have
appointment waiting times that are
immeasurable.
And so, I have trouble
understanding how we can move forward
in a dematerialized field
when, in practice, we won't be able...
I mean, it's nice to have a
digital twin, but if you can't
get treated, what's
the point? So, your question, there
are indeed two issues,
which run in parallel and
move forward together.
And that's why we also work
with institutions
and the top medical directors
of health insurers and others
to see how the demands
will manage to move forward.
First part of the answer:
it's demographic.
Unfortunately, we have a
population that is increasingly
aging, and a number
of healthcare workers that's shrinking.
So factually, we're going to be
more and more in a care crisis.
That's for sure.
We absolutely don't want
to separate the two.
That is to say, the digital
twin, for us, must be
used by the patient and also
by the doctor to be able to
improve patient follow-up.
So that means
that indeed, I agree,
our idea is to say
yes, we have one more tool in
our pocket, but that means
you still always need
to be with your doctor.
So that means we still need
just as many healthcare workers.
What's the answer to
having more healthcare workers tomorrow
and being even better supported?
I don't have the answer.
If I did, I think
it would be fantastic.
Nobody has it today.
And unfortunately, there's this
demographic aspect
that means we have it
less and less, the answer.
Now, what's going to be
interesting is that the...
there are going to be
new, I think, new
coordinators among
healthcare workers emerging.
The big issue,
what you're explaining, ultimately,
ties in with the notion
of care coordination.
Who's going to coordinate care?
Who's going to support us,
humanly speaking, along our
care pathway? We don't have enough
radiologists, we don't
have enough dermatologists.
So ultimately, who's going to do it?
There are healthcare workers, so
nurses, who today have
an already well-established role, but
who can also have this
ability to take on this work of
coordination and to be able to
meet certain needs to
a certain extent.
It doesn't solve every problem,
but there are going to be what we call,
roughly, care coordinators
entering the market.
They could be nurses,
male or female, they could be
other types of healthcare workers, they
could be, why not, APA,
APA coaches, in adapted
physical activity, why not
physiotherapists, who will take on
other roles to come
improve and strengthen
care coordination at the
national level.
So, there are answers,
partial answers,
but on the other hand, the demographic
problem, that one we don't have.